# Abdullah Tabbal

Front-end Software Engineer

abdullahtabbal@outlook.com

+972568707708

linkedin.com/in/abdullahtabbal

github.com/AbdullahPS

A Front-end Software Engineer who seeks a challenging carrier to improve his skills and expand good knowledge in various Programming languages and technologies including JavaScript, ES6, Typescript, HTML, and CSS, java, dart, python, C, flutter. Experienced in Scrum Development and well-known in libraries like Next.js, React.js Material UI, React query. Experience with Node.js, Express.js TAP Cohort 4 graduate at Kiitos Technologies.

### **EDUCATION**

O Birzeit University Bachelor's of Computer System Engineering

2014 - 2020

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Front-end Engineer Internship

Kiitos Technologies - Talent Acceleration Program (TAP)

02/2022 - 05/2022

TAP: An international traineeship program for young professionals to accelerate their careers in tech. It equips the graduates with indemand technical skills, mentorship, career coaching, and realworld project experience.

- Built front-end UIs from Adobe Xd files using Next.js and Material UI
- Integrated front-end Uis with backend to fetch and display data using React Query
- Developed the front-end of a social book sharing platform for a startup in Amsterdam using Next.js, React, TypeScript, and Material UI, following Agile Framework.

# Sales And Advertisement Specialist

Amazon Seller Central

02/2020 - 03/2022 Ramallah Online Amazon Seller Center distributing products from Germany to the

eп

- Managed advertisement campaigns and products to be sold.
- Monitored programs for the company, such as SQL database for inventory level, seller legend application for sales statistics
- Monitored sales, expenses, incomes and inventory level of products and cost of goods.

#### SKILLS



### **PROJECTS**

- Chronic Kidney Disease Predictor and Stone Detector
- Built a system, that recognizes chronic kidney diseases and detects kidney stones based on machine learning and Computer Vision using Python Libraries :Numpy, Open-cv, Skimage, Scipy, Tkinter, Os, Pickle
- Arabic Font Recognition
- Designed an implicit-based character recognizer system that recognize Arabic characters by training a classifier with a data set using LeNet-5 deep-learning approach and using Sliding windows approach as an object detection method
- React Notes App
- Created a simple Application in React mainly in order to learn about the basics features in React using React.js, Material Ui

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic

German

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

### INTERESTS

Android Custom Rom Development Hiking Sports Listening to Music Learning Languages